L’Aerophile Collection
Science, Technology, & Business Division, Library of Congress
- Types of Aircraft (Box 75-117)
  - Gliders. (Box 114)
    - United States. (Envelope 17)
      - Photograph of “Our Trailer, at Sleeping Bear, Michigan” host of the 1938 “National Contest.” (Item 10)
      - An invitation from Wilmington Camera Shop (Delaware), to the “Exhibition of Photographs taken with Zeiss Ikon Cameras.” (Item 11)
      - An envelope from l’Aérophile to Theodore G. Bellak (Wilmington, Delaware; returned to sender; October, 1935). The letter thanks Bellak for pictures from the National Gliding and Soaring Competitions that were used in a recent issue, and returning unused photos. (Item 12)
      - Nine photographs of American gliders. (Item 13)
      - Photograph of Richard C. Dupont after breaking the record for glider flight after traveling 155 miles; July 6, 1934. (Item 14)
      - Photograph of “America’s Latest ‘Flying Wing’ – Revolutionary Northrop Machine Proves 50% More Efficient in California Tests.” (Item 15)
      - Photograph of “Burt B. Brooks of the Washington Glider Club ... taking off in a Franklin utility glider.” (Item 16)
  - Hydroplanes. (Box 115)
    - Britain Short Hydroplanes. (Envelope 1)
    - England Hydroplanes. (Envelope 2)
    - Hydroplane Latécoère (French). (Envelope 3)
    - France Hydroplanes. (Envelope 4)
    - Germany Hydroplanes Dornier. (Envelope 5)
    - Germany Hydroplanes. (Envelope 6)
    - Holland Hydroplanes. (Envelope 7)
    - Italy Hydroplanes. (Envelope 8)
    - Japan Hydroplanes. (Envelope 9)
    - Poland Hydroplanes. (Envelope 10)
    - Portugal Hydroplanes. (Envelope 11)
    - Switzerland Hydroplanes. (Envelope 12)
    - Latham Hydroplanes (France). (Envelope 13)
    - United States Hydroplanes Sikorsky. (Envelope 14)
    - United States Hydroplanes. (Envelope 15)
  - Hydroplanes. (Box 116)
    - Photographs Hydroplanes. (Envelope 1)
    - Photographs Hydroplanes. (Envelope 2)
    - Henri Falore. (Envelope 3)
    - Henri Farmen. (Envelope 4)
    - Donnet Leveque. (Envelope 5)
    - Nieuport. (Envelope 6)
    - “Deperdussin” Hydroplanes. (Envelope 7)
  - Model aircraft. (Box 117)
    - Belgium. (Envelope 1)
    - England. (Envelope 2)
    - France, 1935. (Envelope 3)
    - France #2, 1930s. (Envelope 4)
    - France #3, 1940s. (Envelope 5)
    - France #3A, 1940s. (Envelope 6)
    - France #4. (Envelope 7)
    - Russia. (Envelope 8)
    - United States. (Envelope 9)
    - Unidentified Model Aircraft Photographs. (Envelope 10)
    - Gordon Bennett. (Envelope 11)
- Motors and Engines (Box 120-129)
  Information on companies that produced aircraft motors and engine.
  Alphabetically, by company.
  - Motors and Engines A-B. (Box 120)
    - Motor Accessories. (Envelope 1)
    - Motor Absorbers. (Envelope 2)
    - Accessories for Motors. (Envelope 3)
    - Alpha Romeo Engines. (Envelope 4)
    - Americans Motors. (Envelope 5)
    - Antionette Motors. (Envelope 6)
    - Argus Motors. (Envelope 7)
    - Armstrong Motors. (Envelope 8)
    - Armstrong-Siddeley Engines. (Envelope 9)
    - Armstrong-Siddeley Motors. (Envelope 10)
    - Arrow Engines. (Envelope 11)
    - Aster-Mikron Motors. (Envelope 12)
    - Attachments to Motors. (Envelope 13)
    - Ava Motors. (Envelope 14)
    - Ava Motors. (Envelope 15)
    - “Aviquipo.” (Envelope 16)
    - Bati Motors. (Envelope 17)
    - Bendix Eclipse. (Envelope 18)
    - Bonnet Motors. (Envelope 19)
    - Bramo Motors. (Envelope 20)
    - Bristol Engines. (Envelope 21)
    - Brouhot Motors. (Envelope 22)
    - Burlat Motors. (Envelope 23)
  - Motors and Engines C-E. (Box 121)
    - Canon Gadoux Motors. (Envelope 1)
    - Motors Carburetor. (Envelope 2)
    - Carden Aero Engines. (Envelope 3)
    - Chaise Motors. (Envelope 4)
    - Chenu Motors. (Envelope 5)
    - Cirrus Engines and Motors. (Envelope 6)
    - Clement Bayard Motors. (Envelope 7)
    - Clerget Motors. (Envelope 8)
    - Coatalens Motors. (Envelope 9)
    - Combustibles (Fuel). (Envelope 10)
    - Compressors. (Envelope 11)
    - Compressors. (Envelope 12)
    - Curtiss Wright Motors. (Envelope 13)
    - Curtiss Wright Corporation. (Envelope 14)
    - Curtiss Wright Motors. (Envelope 15)
    - Czech Motors. (Envelope 16)
    - D. Napier & Son Ltd. (Envelope 17)
    - Dansette Motors. (Envelope 18)
    - Darracq Motors. (Envelope 19)
    - Delage Motors. (Envelope 20)
    - Detachable Pieces from Motors. (Envelope 21)
    - Diesel Engines. (Envelope 22)
    - English Motors. (Envelope 23)
  - Motors and Engines F-H. (Box 122)
    - Farcot Motors. (Envelope 1)
    - Farman Motors. (Envelope 2)
    - Favata Motors. (Envelope 3)
    - Fiat Motors. (Envelope 4)
    - Flying Squirrel Engine. (Envelope 5)
    - Garelli Compressor. (Envelope 6)
    - “Generalites” Motors. (Envelope 7)
    - Gnome Motors. (Envelope 8)
    - Gnome Rhone. (Envelope 9)
    - Great Britain Motors. (Envelope 10)
    - Gregoire Motors. (Envelope 11)
    - Dettavilland Motors. (Envelope 12)
    - Motors de Havilland. (Envelope 13)
    - Gipsy Engines. (Envelope 14)
    - Hispano Suiza Motors. (Envelope 15)
  - Motors and Engines I-M. (Box 123)
    - Isotta Fraschini. (Envelope 1)
    - Isotta Fraschini Motors. (Envelope 2)
    - Italian Motors. (Envelope 3)
    - Jumo Motors. (Envelope 4)
    - Laviator Motors. (Envelope 5)
    - Lenape Aircraft & Motors, Inc. (Envelope 6)
    - Lilloise Motor Company. (Envelope 7)
    - Lorraine Motors. (Envelope 8)
    - Lycoming Aviation Engine. (Envelope 9)
    - Mawen Motors. (Envelope 10)
    - Menasco Manufacturing Co. (Envelope 11)
    - Mercedes-Benz Motors. (Envelope 12)
    - Mini Motors. (Envelope 13)
    - Miscellaneous Motors Before WWII. (Envelope 14)
    - Miscellaneous Motors. (Envelope 15)
    - Miscellaneous Motors and Engines. (Envelope 16)
    - Motors (England). (Envelope 17)
    - Miscellaneous Motors (Germany). (Envelope 18)
    - Miscellaneous Motors (Germany). (Envelope 19)
    - Miscellaneous Unknown Motors. (Envelope 20)
    - Model Aircrafts: Motors (France). (Envelope 21)
    - Model Aircrafts: Motors (Germany). (Envelope 22)
    - Model Aircrafts: Motors (Poland). (Envelope 23)
    - Model Aircrafts: Motors (Russia). (Envelope 24)
    - Model Aircraft: Motors (USA). (Envelope 25)
  - Motors and Engines N-P. (Box 124)
    - Nieuport Motors. (Envelope 1)
    - Officine Columbo Motors. (Envelope 2)
    - OHV Motors. (Envelope 3)
    - Packard Motors. (Envelope 4)
    - Panhard Motors. (Envelope 5)
    - Panhard Motors. (Envelope 6)
    - Peugeot Motors. (Envelope 7)
    - Peugeot Motors “Modele Reduit.” (Envelope 8)
    - Pobjoy “R” Engines. (Envelope 9)
    - Piaggio Motors. (Envelope 10)
    - Piaggio Motors. (Envelope 11)
    - Potez Motors. (Envelope 12)
    - Potez Motors. (Envelope 13)
    - Praga Motors. (Envelope 14)
    - Pratt & Whitney Co. (Motors). (Envelope 15)
    - Propulsions. (Envelope 16)
    - Motors-Publications (France). (Envelope 17)
  - Motors and Engines Q-R. (Box 125)
    - R.E.P. Motors. (Envelope 1)
    - Regnier Motors. (Envelope 2)
    - Regnier (“Ste Ame des Etabs”). (Envelope 3)
    - Renault Motors. (Envelope 4)
    - Renault Motors #2. (Envelope 5)
    - Renault Motors (“Ste Ame”). (Envelope 6)
    - Replacement Energy/Gas Generators/Vapor Motors. (Envelope 7)
    - Rhone Motors. (Envelope 8)
    - Rossel Motors. (Envelope 9)
  - Motors and Engines S. (Box 125A)
    - Salmson. (Envelope 1)
    - Salmson #2. (Envelope 2)
    - Salmson Motors. (Envelope 3)
    - Sarolea Motors. (Envelope 4)
    - Societe Nationale de Construction de Moteurs. (Envelope 5)
    - Starter Motor (P. Viet). (Envelope 6)
    - Starter Motors Including Farman. (Envelope 7)
    - Stewit Motors. (Envelope 8)
    - Stewit Engines. (Envelope 9)
    - Szekely Motors. (Envelope 10)
  - Motors and Engines T-Z. (Box 126)
    - Train Motors. (Envelope 1)
    - Vapor Motors. (Envelope 2)
    - Walter Motors. (Envelope 3)
    - Warner Engines. (Envelope 4)
    - Weir Aero Engines. (Envelope 5)
    - Zenith Carburetor. (Envelope 6)
    - Zlinska Letecka. (Envelope 7)
  - Motors and Engines, Rolls-Royce & Junkers Publications. (Box 127)
    - Publication: “Moteur D’Aviation: Jumo 213 A-1 et C-O ‘Junkers’”, 1946. (Item 1)
    - Publication: “Moteurs Rolls-Royce: ‘Merlin’ Types 45-46-47-50-56.” (Item 2)
    - Rolls-Royce #1. (Envelope 1)
      - Brochure, “Moteurs D’Aviation Rolls-Royce,” distributed at the Exposition Aéronautique Internationale De Beograd (Belgrade), 1938. (Item 1)
      - Brochure describing the specifications for the “‘Merlin’ Engine.’” (Item 2)
      - Description of the Merlin “12-cylinder liquid-cooled: 1,050 h.p. (maximum)” engine. (Item 3)
      - Brochure “Moteurs D’Aviation Rolls-Royce.” (Item 4)
      - Press release issued by The Society of British Aircraft Construction Ltd., “Secret British Aero Engine at Paris Show: New Sleeve-Valve Powerplant,” London: November 23, 1938. (Item 5)
      - Publication “Rolls-Royce Merlin Aero Engines” reprinted by The Aeroplane, April 26, 1939. (Item 6)
      - Advertising brochure describing the Rolls-Royce Merlin Engine. (Item 7)
    - Rolls-Royce #2. (Envelope 2)
      - Advertising booklet describing the “Peregrine” motor. (Item 1)
      - Two letters from M. Golovine, of Rolls-Royce, to L’Aérophile, 1936. The first letter responds to L’Aérophile’s request for information pertaining to motors displayed at an upcoming exhibition. The second letter encloses a description (no enclosure) of the “Kestrel” engine, series XIV and XVI. (Item 2)
      - Three advertising booklets that describe Rolls-Royce engines; October, 1936 and November, 1937. (Item 3)
      - Advertisement with specifications for the “Kestrel” engine. (Item 4)
      - Advertising brochure “Rolls-Royce Aero Engines,”, May, 1935. (Item 5)
    - Rolls-Royce #3. (Envelope 3)
      - Advertising pamphlet, “Rolls-Royce Aero Engines,” translated into English, French, and Spanish. (Item 1)
  - Motors and Engines Fiat Publications. (Box 128)
    - Aeronautica D’Italia Torino. (Item 1)
  - Motors and Engines Societe des Moteurs et Automobiles. (Box 129)
    - SGA Lorraine Diagram of an Engine, 1932. (Item 1)
    - Sixteen Pamphlets Containing Specifications and Diagrams from the Societe Des Moteurs Et Automobiles Lorraine, 1930s. (Item 2)
- Aviators and Designers (Box 130-150A)
  Photographs and publications on aviators and aircraft designers.
  Arranged alphabetically, by nationality.
  - France A-BES. (Box 130)
    - Ader, C. (Folder 1)
    - Aime, E. (Folder 2)
    - Airault, F. (Folder 3)
    - Aialbert. (Folder 4)
    - Albert, E. (Folder 5)
    - Albert. (Folder 6)
    - Allard. (Folder 7)
    - Allegre, L. (Folder 8)
    - Amerigo. (Folder 9)
    - Antoinat. (Folder 10)
    - Anzani. (Folder 11)
    - Aqua Vivo. (Folder 12)
    - Archdeacon, E. (Folder 13)
    - Armand, G. (Folder 14)
    - Armengaud. (Folder 15)
    - Armingault. (Folder 16)
    - Arnoux, M. (Folder 17)
    - Arrachart, L. (Folder 18)
    - Assolant. (Folder 19)
    - Aubrun, E. (Folder 20)
    - Audemars, E. (Folder 21)
    - Auger. (Folder 22)
    - Aumont-Thieville. (Folder 23)
    - Avignon, M. (Folder 24)
    - Bach, L. and Boucher, H. (Folder 25)
    - Bachelard, E. (Folder 26)
    - Badin, R. (Folder 27)
    - De Baeder. (Folder 28)
    - Bague. (Folder 29)
    - Bailloud. (Folder 30)
    - Bailly. (Folder 31)
    - Bajac, R. (Folder 32)
    - Balsan, J. (Folder 33)
    - Balzon, J. (Folder 34)
    - Bans, G. (Folder 35)
    - Baratoux, M. (Folder 36)
    - Barbandy, G. (Folder 37)
    - Barbotte, E. (Folder 38)
    - Bardel. (Folder 39)
    - Bares. (Folder 40)
    - Baroncelli. (Folder 41)
    - Barthou, L. #1. (Folder 42)
    - Barthou, L. #2. (Folder 43)
    - Bastie, M. (Folder 44)
    - Bastien, C. (Folder 45)
    - Batelier. (Folder 46)
    - Balthiat, L. (Folder 47)
    - Battini, L. (Folder 48)
    - Baudin. (Folder 49)
    - Barra. (Folder 50)
    - Baudry. (Folder 51)
    - Bayet. (Folder 52)
    - Bazin. (Folder 53)
    - Beauchamp, R. (Folder 54)
    - Beaumont (Conneau). (Folder 55)
    - Beauvais. (Folder 56)
    - Bechereau. (Folder 57)
    - Bedel. (Folder 58)
    - Bellanger. (Folder 59)
    - Bellemont. (Folder 60)
    - Benazet, P. (Folder 61)
    - Benoit. (Folder 62)
    - Benoist, J. (Folder 63)
    - Bequet. (Folder 64)
    - Bereau, L. (Folder 65)
    - Bergeret. (Folder 66)
    - Bernard, J. (Folder 67)
    - Bernard. (Folder 68)
    - Bernard. (Folder 69)
    - Bernstein, L. (Folder 70)
    - Bertin. (Folder 71)
    - Besançon, G. (Folder 72)
    - Besson. (Folder 73)
  - France BES-CAR. (Box 131)
    - Bessonneau, J. (Folder 1)
    - Bibesco. (Folder 2)
    - Biche, J. (Folder 3)
    - Bider, O. (Folder 4)
    - Bidot. (Folder 5)
    - Bielovucic, J. (Folder 6)
    - Bienaimé, R. (Folder 7)
    - Binet. (Folder 8)
    - Blanc. (Folder 9)
    - Blanchard. (Folder 10)
    - Blanchet, G. (Folder 11)
    - Blancpain. (Folder 12)
    - Blanquier. (Folder 13)
    - Bleriot, L. (Folder 14)
    - Blondel. (Folder 15)
    - Bobba. (Folder 16)
    - Boegler. (Folder 17)
    - Bois. (Folder 18)
    - Boivin. (Folder 19)
    - Bokanowski. (Folder 20)
    - Boland, A. (Folder 21)
    - Boland. (Folder 22)
    - Bollée, L. (Folder 23)
    - Bonamy, E. (Folder 24)
    - Bonnet, T. (Folder 25)
    - Bonnier, M. (Folder 26)
    - Bonnier. (Folder 27)
    - Bonnot. (Folder 28)
    - Bonte, A. (Folder 29)
    - Bonzon, M. (Folder 30)
    - Bordé, P. (Folder 31)
    - Boris, H. (Folder 32)
    - Botal, R. (Folder 33)
    - Botty. (Folder 34)
    - Boucher, H. (Folder 35)
    - Boulade, A. (Folder 36)
    - Boulade, L. (Folder 37)
    - Bourdin. (Folder 38)
    - Boureau. (Folder 39)
    - Bourhis. (Folder 40)
    - Bournique, A. (“Pierre-Marie”). (Folder 41)
    - Bossoutrot. (Folder 42)
    - Bouvier. (Folder 43)
    - Bradin. (Folder 44)
    - De Bradsky. (Envelope 1)
    - Brégi, H. (Folder 45)
    - Bréguet, L. (Folder 46)
    - Bresson. (Folder 47)
    - Breyer, J. (Folder 48)
    - Briault. (Folder 49)
    - Bricard, G. (Folder 50)
    - Brineionc des Moulinais. (Folder 51)
    - Brocard. (Folder 52)
    - Broet, T. (Folder 53)
    - Brun. (Folder 54)
    - Bruneau de Laborie. (Folder 55)
    - Brunet. (Folder 56)
    - Buc. (Folder 57)
    - Burgeat. (Folder 58)
    - Buneau-Varilla. (Folder 59)
    - Burri. (Folder 60)
    - Burtin. (Folder 61)
    - Busson, G. (Folder 62)
    - Byasson. (Folder 63)
    - Carillau, P. (Folder 64)
    - Caille. (Folder 65)
    - Callot. (Folder 66)
    - Camine. (Folder 67)
    - Cammerman. (Folder 68)
    - Canel. (Folder 69)
    - Cangardel. (Folder 70)
    - Carlier, A. (Folder 71)
    - Carlier. (Folder 72)
  - France CAS-DA. (Box 132)
    - Carmier. (Folder 1)
    - Carpentier, A. (Folder 2)
    - Carretier. (Folder 3)
    - De Calters (Piérre). (Envelope 1)
    - Carton, E. (Folder 4)
    - Carvin, L. (Folder 5)
    - Castillon de St. Victor. (Envelope 2)
    - Cattaneo. (Folder 6)
    - Caudron Fréres. (Folder 7)
    - de Caumont. (Envelope 3)
    - Causan, A. (Folder 8)
    - Cavalli, G. (Folder 9)
    - Cavelier, M. (Folder 10)
    - Cazaux, L. (Folder 11)
    - Challe. (Folder 12)
    - Chalus. (Folder 13)
    - Chamberrois. (Folder 14)
    - Chamberlin. (Folder 15)
    - Champel. (Folder 16)
    - Chanroux. (Folder 17)
    - Chanteloup. (Folder 18)
    - Chanute, O. (Folder 19)
    - Charriou, A. (Folder 20)
    - Château. (Folder 21)
    - Chateaubrun, G. (Envelope 4)
    - Chaudry. (Folder 22)
    - Chaumié, E. (Folder 23)
    - (de) Chaunac. (Envelope 5)
    - Chavez, G. (Folder 24)
    - Chemet, G. (Folder 25)
    - Cherault. (Folder 26)
    - Cheutin. (Folder 27)
    - Chevalier. (Folder 28)
    - Chevalier. (Folder 29)
    - Chevillard. (Folder 30)
    - Chollat. (Folder 31)
    - Clavenard. (Folder 32)
    - Clavenard. (Folder 33)
    - Clement, M. (Folder 34)
    - Clement-Bayard. (Folder 35)
    - Clerc. (Folder 36)
    - Clerget. (Folder 37)
    - Clouth, R. (Folder 38)
    - Codos. (Folder 39)
    - Coli. (Folder 40)
    - Colliex, M. (Folder 41)
    - Collomb. (Folder 42)
    - Comet. (Folder 43)
    - Contenet. (Folder 44)
    - Corbon. (Folder 45)
    - Corbu. (Folder 46)
    - Cordier, J. (Folder 47)
    - Cormier, G. (Folder 48)
    - Cornet. (Folder 49)
    - Corniglion-Molinier. (Folder 50)
    - Cornu. (Folder 51)
    - Cornuché. (Folder 52)
    - Corot, A. (Folder 53)
    - Costes, D. and Bellonte. (Folder 54)
    - Cot, P. (Folder 55)
    - Couhé, L. (Folder 56)
    - Coupet. (Folder 57)
    - de Courteilles. (Envelope 6)
    - Coutelle. (Folder 58)
    - Couzinet, R. (Folder 59)
    - Crespy. (Folder 60)
    - Crombez. (Folder 61)
    - Crouzon. (Folder 62)
    - de Cuverville. (Envelope 7)
    - Dagneaux, J. (Folder 63)
    - Dalger. (Folder 64)
    - Dard. (Folder 65)
    - Darqué, H. (Folder 66)
    - Dartois, C. (Folder 67)
    - Daucourt. (Folder 68)
    - David, E. (Folder 69)
    - David, M. (Folder 70)
  - France DE-ET. (Box 133)
    - Deat, M. (Folder 1)
    - Debroutelle, P. (Folder 2)
    - Debuissy, A. (Folder 3)
    - Decker-David. (Folder 4)
    - Decauville, P. (Folder 5)
    - Decroo. (Folder 6)
    - Decugis, O. (Folder 7)
    - Defrasse. (Folder 8)
    - Delage. (Folder 9)
    - Delagrange, L. (Folder 10)
    - Delaitre. (Folder 11)
    - Delebecque, J. (Folder 12)
    - Delesalle. (Folder 13)
    - Delmotte, R. (Folder 14)
    - Delobel. (Folder 15)
    - Demazel, L. (Folder 16)
    - Demblanc, L. (Folder 17)
    - Demongeot. (Folder 18)
    - Demain. (Folder 19)
    - Denois, E. (Folder 20)
    - Dentraut. (Folder 21)
    - Depasse, H. (Folder 22)
    - Deperdussin, A. (Folder 23)
    - Deroye. (Folder 24)
    - Descamps. (Folder 25)
    - Desgranges. (Folder 26)
    - Desmanest. (Folder 27)
    - Desparmet. (Folder 28)
    - Destrem. (Folder 29)
    - Marcel Destrem Obituary 1923. (Envelope 1)
    - Detré, G. (Folder 30)
    - Detroyat, M. (Folder 31)
    - Deve, M. (Folder 32)
    - Deutsch de la Meurthe, H. (Folder 33)
    - de Dion (Marquis). (Envelope 2)
    - Divetain, P. (Folder 35)
    - Domergue, J. (Folder 36)
    - Dordilly. (Folder 37)
    - Doret, M. (Folder 38)
    - Doumerc, J. (Folder 39)
    - Doulut. (Folder 40)
    - Dreyfus, G. (Folder 41)
    - Ducrot. (Folder 42)
    - Duhamel. (Folder 43)
    - Dumont. (Folder 44)
    - Duplessis de Grenedan. (Folder 45)
    - Drouhin. (Folder 46)
    - Drouillet. (Folder 47)
    - Dubois, J. (Folder 48)
    - Dubois. (Folder 49)
    - Dubois-LeCour, G. (Folder 50)
    - Dubonnet, E. (Folder 51)
    - Dubost, A. (Folder 52)
    - Dubourdieu. (Folder 53)
    - Dubreuil, G. (Folder 54)
    - Ducourneau. (Folder 55)
    - Dumanois. (Folder 56)
    - Dumesnil. (Folder 57)
    - Dumont, Santos. (Envelope 3)
    - Dupuis. (Folder 58)
    - Durafour, F. (Folder 59)
    - Duray. (Folder 60)
    - Durmon, G. (Folder 61)
    - Durmon, G. (Folder 62)
    - Duroyon. (Folder 63)
    - Duthu, L. (Folder 64)
    - Duval. (Folder 65)
    - Echeman. (Folder 66)
    - Edmond. (Folder 67)
    - Ehrmann. (Folder 68)
    - Eiffel. (Folder 69)
    - Engel. (Folder 70)
    - Elias. (Folder 71)
    - de l’Escaille. (Envelope 4)
    - Esnault-Pelterie, R. (Folder 72)
    - Espanet, G. (Folder 73)
    - d’Esperey, Franchet. (Envelope 5)
    - Espitallier. (Folder 74)
    - d’Estailleur de Chantereine. (Envelope 6)
    - Eteué. (Envelope 7)
  - France FA-GI. (Box 134)
    - Fabre, H. (Folder 1)
    - Faillant. (Folder 2)
    - Farman, H. (Folder 3)
    - Farman, M. (Folder 4)
    - Farman, R. (Folder 5)
    - Faucompré. (Folder 6)
    - Faure, J. (Folder 7)
    - Fauvel, C. (Folder 8)
    - Féquant, P. (Folder 9)
    - Ferber. (Folder 10)
    - Felix. (Folder 11)
    - Ferhert. (Folder 12)
    - Fernandez, A. (Folder 13)
    - Fevrier, G. (Folder 14)
    - Finat, M. (Folder 15)
    - Fischer, J. (Folder 16)
    - Flammarion, C. (Folder 17)
    - Fleurquin. (Folder 18)
    - Fleury, G. (Folder 19)
    - Fonck, R. (Folder 20)
    - de Fonvielde, W. (Folder 21)
    - Forest, F. (Folder 22)
    - Foucaucourt. (Envelope 8)
    - Fourcade. (Folder 23)
    - Fournier, H. (Folder 24)
    - Fourrier-Ruelle, M.R. (Folder 25)
    - Fourny, G. (Folder 26)
    - Francia (Baron Jean). (Envelope 9)
    - Frantz, J. (Folder 27)
    - Frey, A. (Folder 28)
    - Frochot. (Folder 29)
    - Fronval, A. (Folder 30)
    - Fugairon, P. (Folder 31)
    - Gaillard, R. (Folder 32)
    - Garaix. (Folder 33)
    - Garnier. (Folder 34)
    - Gorros, R. (Folder 35)
    - Garsaux. (Folder 36)
    - Gasnier, P. (Folder 37)
    - Gauchet, A. (Folder 38)
    - Gautteron, G. (Folder 39)
    - Gerard, L. (Folder 40)
    - Geyer (Lt). (Envelope 10)
    - Gibert, L. (Folder 42)
    - Gilbert, E. (Folder 43)
    - Gilles. (Folder 44)
    - Girard. (Folder 45)
    - Girardot, L. (Folder 46)
    - Giraud, E. (Folder 47)
    - Giraud. (Folder 48)
    - Girier. (Folder 49)
    - Givon. (Folder 50)
  - France GL-HU. (Box 135)
    - Glorieux, J. (Folder 1)
    - Gobé. (Folder 2)
    - Gobron, J. (Folder 3)
    - Godard, A. (Folder 4)
    - Godard, E. (Folder 5)
    - Godard, E. (Folder 6)
    - Godard, L. (Folder 7)
    - Godard, L. (Folder 8)
    - Godet. (Folder 9)
    - Gon, H. (Folder 10)
    - Gonin. (Folder 11)
    - Gonord. (Folder 12)
    - Goudard, F. (Folder 13)
    - Gougenheim. (Folder 14)
    - Gounouilhou, H. (Folder 15)
    - Gournay, F. (Envelope 1)
    - Goux. (Folder 16)
    - Goys (Général). (Envelope 2)
    - Grade. (Folder 17)
    - de Graffigny, H. (Envelope 3)
    - de Grailly (Lt.). (Envelope 4)
    - Grandjean. (Folder 18)
    - Grandseigne, R. (Folder 19)
    - Granel, M. (Folder 20)
    - Granet, A. (Folder 21)
    - Grase. (Folder 22)
    - Grimaud, P. (Folder 23)
    - Guffroy. (Folder 24)
    - Guilbaud. (Folder 25)
    - Guillaume, C. (Folder 26)
    - Guillaume. (Folder 27)
    - Guillaumet. (Folder 28)
    - Guillaux, M. (Folder 29)
    - Guyon, L. (Folder 30)
    - Guyot, A. (Folder 31)
    - Guynemer, G. (Folder 32)
    - Haegelen, M. (Folder 33)
    - Hagueneau. (Folder 34)
    - Halluin, G. (Folder 35)
    - Happe. (Folder 36)
    - Hauvette-Michelin. (Folder 37)
    - Helen, E. (Folder 38)
    - Hennessy, M. (Folder 39)
    - Herbemont, A. (Folder 40)
    - Herbster, M. (Folder 41)
    - Hergault. (Folder 42)
    - Hermite, G. (Folder 43)
    - Herrera. (Folder 44)
    - Hervé. (Folder 45)
    - Hervieu, G. (Folder 46)
    - Hirschauer Pére. (Folder 47)
    - Hirschauer, L. (Folder 48)
    - Houpert. (Folder 49)
    - Hugony. (Folder 50)
    - Hurard. (Folder 51)
    - Hureau de Villeneuve. (Folder 52)
  - France IM-LEM. (Box 136)
    - Imbrecq. (Folder 1)
    - Janets, E. (Folder 2)
    - Janoir, L. (Folder 3)
    - Janvier. (Folder 4)
    - Japy, A. (Folder 5)
    - Joseph. (Folder 6)
    - Jauneaud. (Folder 7)
    - Jaugey. (Folder 8)
    - Jost. (Folder 9)
    - Juchmes, G. (Folder 10)
    - Julliot, H. (Folder 11)
    - Kahn, M. (Folder 12)
    - Kapferer, H. (Folder 13)
    - Kauffmann, P. (Folder 14)
    - Keller. (Folder 15)
    - Kergariou. (Envelope 1)
    - Kimmerling. (Folder 16)
    - Kinet, D. (Folder 17)
    - Koechlin. (Folder 18)
    - Kraemer. (Folder 19)
    - Kreyder. (Folder 20)
    - Kuhling. (Folder 21)
    - Labouchére. (Folder 22)
    - Labouret. (Folder 23)
    - Laburgue. (Folder 24)
    - La Chambre, G. (Folder 25)
    - Lacombe, Y. (Folder 26)
    - Lacoste. (Folder 27)
    - Ladougne. (Folder 28)
    - Lafannechére. (Folder 29)
    - Lafrete. (Envelope 2)
    - Lagache. (Folder 30)
    - La Grange, A. (Envelope 3)
    - Lahm, F. (Folder 31)
    - Lahm, F. (Folder 32)
    - Laignier. (Folder 33)
    - Lajous (Capitaine). (Envelope 4)
    - Lallier, R. (Folder 34)
    - Lambert. (Envelope 5)
    - Landelle, G. (Envelope 6)
    - Landowski. (Folder 35)
    - Landron, P. (Folder 36)
    - Landry. (Folder 37)
    - Lanser. (Folder 38)
    - Lantheaume. (Folder 39)
    - Laporte. (Folder 40)